First, let's take a look at the interface of the CLO software.
In the process of operation, to make it easier for everyone to see the demonstration,
the light indicator will be displayed in yellow, and when the left button is pressed, a red circle will appear, and when the right button is pressed, a gradient will appear.
Open the software, there are two large windows in the middle, namely the 3D window and the 2D window.
The left is the 3D window.
In the 3D window, you can simulate virtual clothing, make 360-degree checks and adjust the shape.
The right is the 2D window.
Here you can create a template, edit and sew the template.
In the window, the upper left corner is the vertical menu bar, which controls the information display and hidden in the window.
On both sides of these two windows,
you can see the 3D tool bar and the 2D tool bar corresponding to each other.
These tools will be introduced in more detail later.
Next, look at the top menu bar.
You can create, open storage projects or clothing files, and import and export files.
The edit menu covers the removal, recovery, copy, paste and other common operations and shortcuts.
The right is about 3D.
The left side is about 3D and the bottom bar covers the 2D design.
Both sets of these tools are 2D.
You can change the language here.
You can also change the language here.
newee
Enter the user self-defined window.
You can check or modify the Try Control鍵 and adjust it according to your default mouse key.
to change the software unit, appearance, tool bar position and version line appearance, etc.
If you need to restore the initial state, click on the reset button in the lower left corner.
In the help option on the right side of the settings,
you can open the official manual that supports four languages,
and the detailed explanation of the unlock function.
If you see the hello and blue characters on the right side,
it is your account ID.
The pink icon on the right is called CLO AI Studio.
You can use functions such as AI face changing, AI voiceover, etc.
to make 3D clothing images real.
For the first time, please refer to the tutorial guide at the bottom of the video to activate the AI function.
The button in blue on the right side is the library.
Click on the open library window.
In the library, you can call CLO to bring materials at any time,
connect local materials,
or download resources from the CLOSET platform.
First, see the CLO default library.
There are software-brought clothing, models, fabrics, accessories and scene materials.
For example, what you see now is the clothing folder.
The corresponding content is displayed on the right side.
You can control the display of the content by using the icon in the upper right corner of the window.
For example, icon display or list display.
If you want to check the specific content of a single object,
you can click on the display preview icon in the upper right corner.
Click on the list of materials.
Preview on the right side.
For clothing files, you can double-click,
or drag them to the work area to open.
Here, select a dresser to open.
If there is more material,
you can search in the box above,
and unlock the file by unlocking the keyword.
Next, load a virtual model.
Click on the virtual model folder,
and open the female model folder.
There are four female models in it.
Among them, Luna is a female youth model,
and the rest are adult models.
If the material name shows a small square in front,
it means that the material has not been downloaded.
Use as needed.
You can select a square,
click on the download button in the upper right corner to download.
In addition,
we can also change the configuration,
posture and size of the model.
When there are more female files in the file folder,
we can check the file folder path at the top,
or directly click on a file layer to return to the layer.
Choose to open an adult model,
in addition to the double-click to drag and drop,
you can also right-click on the model to add to the work area.
Click to confirm to add a model.
In addition, right-click on the material,
you can also copy the path,
that is, save the local path of this material,
and copy it to the pasteboard.
You can also click on the resource manager to display.
You can directly open the local file folder where the material is located.
Visit the local path.
This is the CLO default library.
There is also CLOSET Connect next to it.
In the CLOSET label,
you can visit the digital resources managed on the cloud platform through the login account.
In the CONNECT label,
you can visit the public mall,
purchase and download a large amount of resources.
If you have a local material file,
you can click on the plus sign to create a new library,
and connect the material to my library.
It is convenient to quickly call local files in the software.
Click the blue icon again to close the library.
You can also use the shortcut Y.
The simulation displayed on the right side of the library
indicates that the current software is in the simulation mode.
Click to download the menu.
You can switch to the print and export mode,
and the fabric calculation mode.
Next, see the side bar on the left side of the software window.
Click on the history record.
Open the history record window.
Every step you do will be recorded here.
You can click on the steps above to return to the previous state.
If you want to record the current clothing status,
you can click on the record 3D clothing status button.
After the modification,
the clothing record before the double click
can be opened or added to the work area.
Click on the small arrow in the upper right corner
to close the history record.
There is also a module library below.
Use the module library to create and call the clothing module components.
Free combination to get more design solutions.
On the right side of the software window is the object window.
You can manage all the material information,
such as fabric, stickers, buttons, eyes, lines, etc.
Select a certain material,
for example, default fabric.
The attribute editor below
will display its specific material and physical properties,
and then adjust the properties.
Finally, at the bottom of the window,
the bottom left is the version number,
and the bottom right is the interface layout control button.
The first is default status, 3D.
3D, 2D windows display at the same time.
3D only displays 3D windows.
2D only displays 2D windows.
Finally, the reset button.
When the screen layout deviates,
you can reset it back to default layout.
Next, learn the basic operation of software to try to control.
Due to the difference between Windows and Mac systems,
both try to control different buttons.
You can confirm the button in the user's custom control in the settings.
This video will use the default settings in Windows system for demonstration.
You can see that in the preset,
the parallel is the middle key of the mouse,
which is the wheel.
3D rotation needs to use the right key of the mouse.
Close the user's custom window.
Let's try it.
See the 3D window,
see the 3D window,
roll, roll, zoom in and zoom out.
Press and hold the roll to move up and down.
Press and hold the mouse to move the right key,
do not loosen,
and rotate.
When you click on a certain object,
it will rotate with the selected point as the center 360 degrees.
When you need to check the 3D window at some fixed angles,
you can press and hold the right button in the background of the 3D window,
and select the common view to switch.
We can also use the corresponding shortcut key
to combine the small digital keyboard to assist memory.
For example, imagine a model standing in the position of 5,
facing the number 2.
Then 2 is the front of the model.
4 and 6 are the two sides of the model.
With this type of push,
you can switch to some fixed angles more quickly.
The same goes for the 2D window.
Roll, roll, zoom in and zoom out.
Press and hold the roll to move up and down.
Note that the 2D window is flat,
no rotation.
In the 3D or 2D window blank area,
right-click to select the 3D or 2D window.
All objects in the 3D or 2D window
will be displayed in the picture
in a suitable proportion.
If you want to check a specific object,
in the 3D or 2D window,
after selecting the object,
press the shortcut key F
to move the object quickly to the center of the screen,
including the panel, virtual model,
copy and paste, etc.
We just selected the model or panel
through the left-click.
Now let's take a closer look at the 3D and 2D selection tools.
First, let's go to the upper left corner.
New project.
Create a new project.
Press the shortcut key Y to open the window.
Go to the Connect label.
In the selection box,
select the official account Clothraining.
On this basis,
search for the material of our course
and quickly log in.
This is a free material.
We can directly double-click to open it.
Press the shortcut key Y again to close the picture.
See the 3D tool bar below.
At this time, the 3D tool bar
shows the tool with a blue highlight.
Select the mobile tool.
It indicates that the tool is in use.
Stop the mouse on it.
You can check the name of the tool
and the shortcut key Q.
You can click on the link to the manual or video
to check the function description.
Use the select mobile tool.
On the 3D costume,
left-click.
You can see the selected version
with a yellow highlight.
And at the same time,
the outline of the plate
corresponding to the 2D window
also shows a yellow highlight.
Click on the 3D window
to any blank area.
You can cancel the selection.
If you want to double-click,
press the Shift key to double-click
or select.
If you want to full-click,
use the shortcut key Ctrl plus A
to full-click.
You can see the 2D window again.
At this time,
the 2D tool bar
shows the tool with a blue highlight.
To adjust the plate tool,
press the shortcut key A.
Use the adjustment plate tool.
On the plate,
left-click.
You can see that the selected plate edge
shows a yellow highlight.
At the same time,
the plate corresponding to the 3D costume
also shows a yellow highlight.
It can be seen that the selection state
of the 3D and 2D plates is the same.
Click on any blank area
to cancel the selection.
If you want to double-click,
press the Shift key to double-click
or select.
Use the shortcut key Ctrl plus A
to full-click.
In addition,
you can also select the frame
in the 2D window.
Left-click to drag the blank area.
The plate in the empty frame
will be selected together
after loosening the mouse.
If it is just a partial area
of the selected plate,
you can press Ctrl to select.
Then loosen the mouse.
Then the selected plate
will also be selected.
Sometimes,
irregular frames
may also be selected.
Double-click to start in the blank area.
Then left-click to
establish the top of the irregular selection frame.
Finally,
go back to the starting point
and select the content of the frame together.
You can also
use the Ctrl key
to select the entire frame.
Press the shortcut key Y
to open the canvas.
Select a female model.
On the model,
right-click to increase to the work area.
Note that in the pop-up window,
select the option
to open the size and position in the costume.
Then click to confirm
and close the canvas.
Now,
the position of the 3D costume and the model
does not match.
Let's use the move tool
to move the 3D costume to the model.
In the 3D window,
still use the select move tool
to select the 3D costume.
Here is a little trick.
We can double-click
on the plate
to select all the plates
that have a sewing relationship.
Then this whole chain group
and then in any position of the costume,
left-click to drag
to move the costume.
Because the space movement is three-dimensional,
the mouse input
is based on the two-dimensional plane,
so this kind of operation
will cause the movement of the costume
to not meet the expected,
so it is not easy to control.
Therefore, it is recommended that
everyone use the positioning ball
to make more accurate movements.
When we select the 3D costume,
left-click on any position on the costume,
there will be a 3-line straight axis,
three arcs
and a square between the straight lines
to form the positioning ball tool.
The straight axis is used to control the parallel,
the arc controls the rotation,
and the square controls the parallel
in the plane.
There are three types of positioning balls
in the software,
respectively,
screen coordinates,
world coordinates
and horizontal coordinates.
What we are using now
is the screen coordinates.
The axis of the screen coordinate positioning ball
depends on your perspective.
When looking to try to change,
the axis of the positioning ball
will rotate with the camera.
For example, if you rotate the perspective,
you can find that the red axis
is always the left and right direction
of your current perspective.
Find the coordinates
on the right-click of the 3D blank area
and switch to the world coordinates.
The world coordinates
and the appearance of the screen coordinates
are slightly different.
It is made up of three two-way arrows,
three complete arcs
and three square surfaces.
The world coordinates positioning ball
is the basic axis of three-dimensional space.
As the axis of the positioning ball,
it has nothing to do with the screen and the object.
For example, if you rotate the perspective,
you can see that the red axis
is always pointing
to the left and right direction of the model,
which is the x-axis direction of 3D space.
When using the world coordinates,
when the arc and the straight line overlap,
pay attention to the need
to rotate the perspective slightly
to prevent the line overlap
from affecting the choice.
The horizontal coordinates
and the positioning ball
follow the object.
The axis of the positioning ball
appears in the orientation direction itself.
It is mainly used to adjust the virtual model joints
and to use it when designing movements.
Next, we use the positioning ball
to put the costume on the model.
You can try it.
Choose the positioning ball type
that you are used to.
Here we use the screen coordinates
for demonstration.
First, press the shortcut 2
to the front of the model.
Move the costume
to the front of the virtual model.
Then press the shortcut 4 or 6
to the side of the model.
Move the costume to the model.
This ensures that the costume
is worn on the model
in the direction of the policy.
After wearing it,
rotate the angle to confirm
whether it is placed correctly.
Pay attention to the moving process.
You need to keep the whole costume
selected together,
then move it,
otherwise only one version will appear.
The whole costume
does not follow the movement.
In the window,
you can see that
when moving the 3D costume,
the 2D panel will not be misplaced.
Similarly,
use the adjustment panel tool
in the 2D window
to drag the moving panel.
The position of the 3D costume
will not be affected.
After the costume and model are matched,
we need to start the simulation.
Simulate the real fabric spiral
so that the costume is worn on the model.
Use the first tool in the upper left corner
to start the simulation.
When starting the simulation,
the 3D window will simulate
the real weight effect.
The panel will also show
the real soft fabric properties.
At this time,
the mouse will become a small grip
to adjust the shape of the costume.
You can left-click to drag the dress
to adjust the shape.
The shortcut key for simulation
is the control key.
Left-click to press the simulation tool.
Here are three different
simulation modes
to adapt to different work stages.
Normal speed default simulation mode
This is the most common mode.
Use it when making costumes.
Try the fabric properties
to calculate the simulation mode.
This mode will calculate
the physical properties
of the simulated fabric more accurately.
If you need to observe
the real fabric spiral
or the strength of the fabric,
it is recommended to switch to this option.
In contrast,
the calculation of this mode
is relatively advanced.
Animation completion simulation mode
Use it when making animation.
In addition,
at the bottom of the menu,
you can also choose
to calculate the engine as CPU or GPU.
GPU simulation can maintain
the same simulation accuracy
than the speed of CPU simulation.
Therefore,
it is more recommended to use the GPU simulation mode.
Switch to GPU simulation.
You can see that
the simulation icon will
turn from the 10-star arrow
to the down-to-earth air star arrow.
Press the control grid button to start the simulation.
The icon will turn blue.
Press the control grid button
to stop the simulation
and it will turn gray.
This is convenient for us to judge
the current simulation mode
and the calculation engine.
Finally,
let's take a look at the
simulation mode.
This is the simulation mode
of the GPU simulation mode.
of the GPU simulation mode
for GPU simulation.
In this simulation mode,
the resulting resolution
level may be more 0.6ARE
or
2500 px.
The simulation mode
betrayed the simulation mode.
If the simulation mode
is set to 0,
the simulation modul
can be read as 0.6
or 300 px.
However,
when switching spin
the simulation mode
You can hide the inner line and the base line.
In addition, you can see the blue icon in the vertical menu bar.
Clothing
Now 3D clothing is displayed on the surface of the fabric.
The surface of the 3D clothing shows that the fabric is real fabric, and the reverse shows that it is gray.
It can be distinguished by the opposite of the fabric, and the thickness of the fabric in this state is not displayed.
After the general completion of the clothing, we can render the clothing type.
Switch to the surface of the dense fabric, the 3D clothing will show the real thickness of the fabric and the exact back fabric.
Finally, we can save the finished clothing file.
Find the left corner file, save the project file, and set the file name in the pop-up window.
At the same time,
note that the file format we save is ZPRJ, which is the most commonly used project file format in CLO.
The file will contain 3D clothing, virtual models, rendering attribute settings, animation information, and other information such as color.
In addition, the common format in CLO also contains ZPAC clothing files,
AVT virtual model files, ZFAB fabric files,
BTN button buttons, and so on.